# AUDREY THOMASSON

**UI/UX DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER** 

#### Contact



615.200.8357



audreyux dev@gmail.com



github.com/audreythomasson



linkedin.com/in/audrey-thomasson

## **ABOUT**

A designer with management experience currently adding HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, and UI/UX design to my skillset. I am originally from Texas where I earned my degree in Graphic Design at Texas State University just outside of Austin. Since moving to Nashville in 2009, I have had the opportunity to explore the city while photographing real estate. I love the artistic side of real estate photography but I recently I found myself researching software development. I've always been fascinated with the tech industry and I am thrilled to get the opportunity to learn programming skills at a place like Nashville Software School. I can't wait to join the working tech community!

## **EXPERIENCE**

## UI/UX DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER (APPRENTICESHIP)

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL 2020 - CURRENT

- Intensive full-time six-month bootcamp focusing on front-end development, UI/UX fundamentals, problem-solving and working in a remote team environment
- · Built single page apps individually and by teams with full CRUD functionality
- Focus on user experience with intentional design around speed, efficiency, and functionality
- · Utilize source code version control with Git/GitHub
- · Main technologies covered: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, JSON, Node.js, Git, and GitHub

#### FRONT-END CAPSTONE PROJECT: TRAVELSHOTS

Time to complete: 2 Weeks - October 2020

Website that lets traveling photographers save and organize photo shoot ideas

- Built to demonstrate my knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React
- · Incorporates Semantic UI external component library
- · Cloudinary API is used to store and manage images uploaded by the user
- All data including the created Cloudinary image link is stored in a JSON server
- · Saved ideas for the shot list have full CRUD (Create, Read, Update, and Delete)

https://github.com/AudreyThomasson/capstone-react-travel-shots

### REAL ESTATE PHOTOGRAPHER & MARKETING MANAGER

FREELANCE- NASHVILLE, TN: 2010 - 2020

- Photograph and film real estate for MLS listings primarily with a large Keller Williams group as well as independent agents and property owners
- · Documented property specs and researched property information
- · Listed properties on MLS and wrote marketing information and captions
- · Launched marketing materials for listings on various websites

## **Tools & Technology**

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

ReactJS

Visual Studio Code

NPM

JSON Server

Figma

Sass

FireBase

**Bootstrap** 

Semantic UI

Slack

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Git and GitHub version control

Command line work flow

Springer-Miller Host & SpaSoft

EZ Labor Payroll

MindBody Online Scheduling Software

## **Skills**

**User Testing** 

**UX Research** 

**User Personas** 

Wireframes

**Usability Testing** 

Journey Mapping

Interactive Prototypes / Mockups

Remote Teamwork

## **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

#### ASSISTANT MARKETING MANAGER

JOYMOVES PILATES STUDIO- AUSTIN, TX: 2007 - 2010

- · Design marketing materials including online content, direct mail pieces, business cards, ads
- Write and edit copy for marketing materials
- · Photography Pilates Studio and pilates poses for use in print and online
- Log transactions and attendance in MindBody Online Scheduling Software, insure accuracy
  of all billing procedures
- · Interview potential job candidates and train new hires
- · Continue design services on freelance basis after move to Nashville

### SPA SUPERVISOR

LAKE AUSTIN SPA RESORT- AUSTIN, TX: 2004 - 2007

- Responsible for daily operation of 25,000 sq ft luxury spa facility with a staff of over 130
- Provide customer service to a high-end clientele while developing and executing all policies and standards of customer service to maintain five star service reputation
- Forecast business levels to ensure that the spa is staffed appropriately including daily management of over 50 therapists' schedules to provide treatments for over 100 daily guests
- · Hire and train coordinators and locker room attendants
- · Monitor and insure accuracy of all billing procedures for spa and resort guests
- Guest & employee problem resolution
- Order products and maintain inventory including coordination of product (kits) for treatments

#### DESIGNER / PRODUCTION MANAGER

UNITED PARENTING PUBLICATIONS- DALLAS, TX: 2001 - 2003

- · Designed classified ads and page layouts for 22 unique monthly parenting magazines
- · Organized workflow for production department and tracked status of all ads in production
- · Coordinated ad creation and changes with sales staff in home office as well as other states
- · Insured accuracy of all ads, layouts and files transmitted to printing facility
- Adhered to strict printing schedule while meeting all deadlines
- Designed marketing promotions for the sales staff to increase revenue

## **Education**

UI/UX Design & Front-End Development

Nashville Software School Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS, Cum Laude Communication / Graphic Design

**Texas State University**